Bio

Joe Letchford is a graphic designer from Richmond, Virginia. He specializes in graphic design, web design, art direction, visual identity systems, publications, and various print media in the commercial and cultural sectors. Together with Josh Osborne, he runs the enthusiastic, non-geographic studio, Tiny Chime.

He believes strongly in experimentation and collaboration. His creative process endeavors to achieve meaning through dialogue and close partnerships within the specifications of each project.

Experience

March 2018 → Current / San Francisco, CA Google Brand Studio

Freelance Visual designer for Google's in-house brand studio focusing on branding, web design, print design, and art direction.

June 2017 → March 2018 / Washington, DC Design Army

Senior designer at Design Army focusing on branding, web design, and print. Primary web designer for the agency and 2+ additional clients. Regularly managed 8+ projects concurrently with strict deadlines. Delivered 8+ complete projects to agency in my 10 month tenure.

July 2015 → May 2017 / Minneapolis, MN MCAD DesignWorks

Graphic designer for the Minneapolis College of Art and Design in-house studio focusing on exhibition identity, branding, print, and publication design. Responsible for 12+ advertisements and publications for the college and 3 outside clients.

February 2015 → May 2015 / Richmond, VA RiggsWard—Freelance graphic designer

February 2014 → January 2015 / Richmond, VA Epiphany Studio—Junior Designer

Education

Minneapolis College of Art and Design Minneapolis, MN MFA in Visual Studies, 2017.

Virginia Commonwealth University Richmond, VA. BA in Anthropology, 2014.

Proficiencies

Branding, Identity, Web Design, Brand Development, Art Direction, Collateral Design, Print and Publication Design, Rapid Prototyping, HTML, CSS, Adobe Suite, Sketch.

References

Wade Convay Group Creative Lead, Google convay@google.com

Dylan Cole Studio Manager, MCAD DesignWorks dcole@mcad.edu 616.802.0614

Josh Osborne Design Technologist, NPR josborne@npr.org 202.617.5228 josh.graphics